Who of the teacher, who teaches is,
老师是谁，教的是谁，
is important because we teach who we are, always.
这很重要，因为我们教的是我们自己，永远都是。
I think you can test this empirically.
我想你可以用经验来检验这一点。
I was recently invited to go back
最近我被邀请
to my alma mater the college from
回到我的母校，
which I graduated 40 years ago.
也就是我40年前毕业的那所大学。
And on that campus alive and well thank God are
在那个校园里，感谢上天，
three of the great teachers that I had
18至22岁时教过我的
when I was 18 to 22 years old.
三位伟大的老师还活着。
And the college did a brilliant thing,
学院做了一件了不起的事情，
they invited those three men now
他们邀请这三个人现在
in their late 70s and early 80s.
已经是七八十岁的老人。
And me to sit on a panel for two hours
当时我要在几百人面前，
in front of several hundred people.
参与两个小时的讨论组。
And talk about teaching, talk about mentoring.
在这个过程中，谈谈教学和指导。
And it was a remarkable occasion,
这是一个了不起的场合，
for one thing I was able to look at all of them
因为有一件事，我能够看着这三位老师，
and say 40 years ago,
说，40年前，
you guys were a lot older than me than you are today,
你们比我大得多，比你们今天大得多，
which is one of the wonderful things to look back on.
这是后头看中美妙事情之一。
But in the middle of that conversation,
但在那次谈话的中间，
somebody from the audience said,
观众中有人说：
Parker, what courses did you have
“帕克，你从这三位伟大的教授
from these three great professors?
那里学到了什么课程？”
And I could not remember even the title of a course,
而我甚至连课程的名称都记不住，
let alone the information in that course
更不用说那门课程中的信息了，
that I doubtless learned at the time.
不过我当时无疑学到了很多东西。
Because the impact of those three teachers on my life
因为这三位老师对我生命的影响
had nothing to do with course titles or course content,
与课程名称或课程内容无关，
it had everything to do with the selfhood
而与这三位老师的
of those three teachers.
自我身份有关。
These were three people of great integrity
这是三个身心非常完整的人，
and they were my teachers
他们是我的老师，
because I wanted to be like them when I grew up.
因为我希望长大后能像他们一样。
It turned out ultimately of course that
当然，最终的结果是
I had to find my my own sense of self.
我必须找到我自己的自我意识。
But the impact of any teacher is ultimately from selfhood
任何老师的影响力最终都是来自于自我意识，
and not from course, content.
而不是来自于其所教授的课程或内容。
I don't mean to be little course, content,
我并不是说课程和内容不重要，
these courses are the vehicles through which
这些课程是一些
some good things can happen.
好事情发生的载体。
And yes we need knowledge and yes we need theory
是的，我们需要知识；是的，我们需要理论；
and yes we need applications of all of that to the world.
是的，我们需要将所有这些应用到世界上。
But teaching is such an exchange
但是，教学是这样一种从自我
of deep to deep of oneself to another self,
到另一个自我的深入交流，
if it's going to work that who teaches turns out
如果它要发挥作用，那么谁来教
to be an absolutely critical question.
就是一个绝对关键的问题。
Now it's a question that's never
一般来说，这个问题现在
addressed in schools of education,
在教育学校中从未被解决，
it's never addressed in higher education, generally.
在高等教育中也从未被解决。
In higher education generally,
在一般的高等教育中，
the who, the self, the subjectivity is swept under the rug,
"谁"、"自我"、"主观性" 被扫除在地毯之下，
it's regarded as dangerous,
它们被认为是危险的。
it's regarded as something to be factored out,
它们被认为是要被排除在外的东西，
so that we can be objective.
这样我们才能客观。
But that's wrong.
但这种观念是错误的。
It's wrong not only because
这是错的，不仅因为
it creates deformed teaching and learning,
它创造了畸形的教和学，
unreal teaching and learning.
以及不真实的教和学。
But it's wrong because that's just it's not real,
它是错误的，因为那非常不真实的，
it's not the way life happens.
那不是生活发生的方式。
The investment of self is
将心注入是
how we know things in the first place.
我们认识事物的首要方式。
And the investment of the teachers self
在我所见过的每个案例中，
in the subject and in the students is
教师将心注入学科和学生是
how learning happens in every case I've ever seen.
让学习发生的方式。